# Vamsi Krishna Palaparti

I am a Computer Science graduate with 2 years of professional experience in the IT field in an MNC company in India and currently pursuing my Master's in Advanced Computer Science at the University of Leicester, UK. I am a passionate Full-Stack and Software developer, and my professional goal is to work as a Graduate Software Engineer in a reputed company.

+44 - 07824066351 vamsi26081997@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/vamsi-krishna-palaparti/

### **Experience**

## System Engineer - Infosys LTD, Hyderabad, India - November 2019 - September 2021.

- Scored 87% in extensive training for 4 months in Core technologies in the World's largest corporate education center i.e., Infosys' Global Education Center (GEC), Mysuru, India and stood among the top 5 in the class which covered modules like Python and Core Java, DBMS, Personality development and Soft-skills, and MEAN stack Development (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js).
- Successfully worked on a project for the leading Banking organization of America as my client on masking/hiding the sensitive data of around 100s tables as per the client requirements. Sensitive data of tables include information such as SSN, Personal Information, and Bank Account details.
- Used Hive DB (Hadoop and Java) for importing and exporting tables using Hive queries and Python scripts for going through files recursively and finding the sensitive data.
- Actively communicated with the clients in the USA to ensure the projects delivered are felicitous and timely.
- Skillfully coached and tutored over 15 staff members who are newly associated with the project.

### Customer Assistant (Part-time) - Marks and Spencer (M & S), Leicester, UK - Oct 2021 - present.

• Delivering a great shopping experience for customers and proving 'best in town' standards.

### Intern - Bharat Dynamics LTD, Hyderabad, India. - May 2018 - June 2018.

• Completed a web project called 'File Tracking System'. This website keeps track of the files and serves as a medium for sending and receiving the files in an organization and displays the status of the file in a department.

### **Skills**

- Core technologies Java, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Front-End frameworks React.js, Angular.
- Back-End frameworks Node.js and Express, Spring and SpringBoot.
- Databases DBMS (SQL) and NoSQL (MongoDB, GraphQL).
- DevOps technologies Dockers and Kubernetes, CI/CD pipeline, Jenkins, GitHub, JIRA, and more.
- Cloud technologies AWS, Azure, and Heroku.
- Excellent team player and often took leadership duties in project management
- Proficient in English and capable of having effectual communication.
- Willingness to learn new things and adaptability to current situations.
- Skillful problem solver and repeatedly gained several appreciations from seniors.

### **Personal Projects**

### Mr. Movies (08/2021 - present) - mrmovies.herokuapp.com

- Mr. Movies is a movies information website where viewers can get information about movies, actors, directors, and genres.
- Single-Page Application. Used React.js as a front-end framework, Express.js and Node.js as a backend framework, MongoDBAtlas and Firebase as databases, and Heroku to host the application.
- The website includes features like Slideshow, search based on movies, actors, directors, and genres, Recent and Recently Viewed, Wishlisting, Top User hits, Celebrity Spotlight, Sorting and Filtering based on ratings, total votes, budget, revenue, genres, runtime, and release date, Titles respective of years, franchises, etc. Users can also have discussions and comments on respective titles. Achieved Sign-in, registering of users using Google Firebase authentication, and titles data is stored in MongoDBAtlas cloud and user data in Firebase.

# E-Kart and Wanderlust (03/2020 - 06/2020) - Infosys mock projects.

- Ekart is an E-commerce shopping mock website where people can view products of various categories and purchase them. Wanderlust is a travel-based mock website where viewers can search packages and book them.
- Single-Page Applications. Used Angular 5 as a front-end framework, SpringBoot as a back-end framework, MongoDB and MySQL as databases, and Infosys private repository to host it. Implemented many functionalities like Login Authentication, Registration, Recommended Products, Deals Wishlisting and Place Order for Ekart and Verification using SHA-256, Carousel, Pagination, Searching Packages with suggestions, Sorting and Booking a Package for Wanderlust.

### **Achievements**

- Served as the President of Microsoft Innovation Center (MIC), a student body responsible for Microsoft-related trainings and events in the college, and selected as Microsoft Regional Champion for Microsoft Office Specialist (MOS) and Microsoft Technical Associate (MTA).
- Organized Paper Presentations as a part of a technical fest called 'Aagma' in the college.
- Completed several Infosys certifications in Web Development, Java, Python, and Big Data under Infosys Education Platform.

### **Education**

# University of Leicester, Leicester, United Kingdom - Master's in Advanced Computer Science

- Sept 2021 Sept 2022.
- Studying modules like Advanced Web Technologies, Mobile and Web Applications, Big Data, and Predictive Analysis.

# Anurag Group of Institutions, Hyderabad, India - Bachelor's in Computer Science.

- July 2015 April 2019.
- Scored an overall CGPA of 8.67 out of 10 without any backlogs.
- Completed courses like C, C++ with OOP concepts, Java, Python, Web Technologies, Big Data, Cloud Computing, Machine Learning, DBMS.

# Sri Chaitanya Junior College, Hyderabad, India - An intermediate course in MPC.

- July 2013 April 2015.
- Scored 85%.
- MPC Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry.

# Sri Chaitanya Techno School, Hyderabad, India - High School education.

• Scored 9.5 CGPA out of 10.